

Charlie Gunning

chas90@gmail.com | +44 (0) 7904 475365

PERSONAL

I am a self-driven individual with over five years of SQL development experience, including being the lead developer on multiple key business projects across my career to date. I have a clear, logical mind with a practical approach to problemsolving and a drive to see deliverables through to completion. I am a keen learner and have a genuine passion for SQL, but have also pushed myself to proactively learn other languages and tools – including C#, JavaScript, HTML and Tableau – to strengthen my skillset and evidence my eagerness to progress in self-development.

EDUCATION, TRAINING & ACHIEVEMENTS

MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (MITX)

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python

Pass (98%)

INTERNATIONAL SOFTWARE TESTING QUALIFICATIONS BOARD (ISTQB)

Nov 2017 - Nov 2017

ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level

Pass

WESTCLIFF HIGH SCHOOL FOR BOYS (SIXTH FORM COLLEGE)

Sep 2001 – Sep 2008

A-Level Geology B AS-Level Chemistry B A-Level Physics C AS-Level Mathematics D

10 x GCSE A* - C

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Weekly awards for taking ownership, great communication and supporting other teams in the business.
- Quarterly awards for actively seeking cross-skilling opportunities, instilling a one-team ethos, and supporting other teams by leading Excel training sessions
- Annual awards for quickly becoming a valued member of the team and taking ownership with self-development and seeking out opportunities to encourage improvements within the team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WILMINGTON HEALTHCARE/WILMINGTON PLC

Jul 2019 - Present

SQL Developer

- Design, implementation and maintenance of the business' data and information solutions.
- Supporting the above by using tools and software including Tableau, Git, GitHub and Visual Studio Code.
- Processing and anonymising sensitive healthcare information, including data from NHS Digital.
- Introducing new ideas and best-practices learned from previous employment to streamline existing processes.
- Proactively learning C# and Tableau outside of work to broaden knowledge and share experiences.
- Creating applications using Electron (Chromium, Node.js, HTML/CSS/JavaScript) to improve business processes.
- Solely producing a new user management tool which has received positive feedback from the business and reduced manual overhead and delivery times.

SKIPTON BUILDING SOCIETY

Sep 2015 - Apr 2019

Business Intelligence (BI) Specialist

- Design, implementation, and maintenance of the business' Operational Data Store (ODS) and Data Warehouse.
- Creation and maintenance of SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) packages to aid with the above process through Visual Studio (VS 2013).
- Promoting code through different environments (i.e. Test/UAT/Pre-Production/Production) through Source Control.

- Performing systems testing on solutions built by developers and reporting defects through Team Foundation Server (TFS 2012).
- Extensive use of SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS 2008/2014) to create and alter tables and stored
 procedures as well as frequent querying of the ODS/DW for reporting and analysis.
- Use of SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS 2008), Report Builder (2008/2014), SharePoint lists and Excel to produce reports for the business based on data from ODS/DW and other sources.
- Consistently being recognised for the above responsibilities and extra work through weekly, monthly, quarterly, and annual awards within the department.

SKIPTON BUILDING SOCIETY

Mar 2015 – Sep 2015

Customer Adviser

- Being the first point of contact for new and existing customers of the Society.
- Handling day-to-day transactions within a Financial Services environment (e.g. account deposits, withdrawals, openings, closures).
- Assessing customers' needs to inform them of products and services relevant to their situation and refer them to formal advice if necessary.
- Offered Business Intelligence position at the Society's Head Office within probationary period.

TRUSTFORD WILMSLOW

Sep 2014 - Feb 2015

Used Car Sales Executive

- Assisting new and existing customers in buying used cars and being the main point of contact for any issues.
- Identifying customers' needs to help find the right car and offer test drives/demonstrations.
- Joint-highest score ever achieved for examinations at the end of training without prior car sales experience.

LADBROKES PLC Jul 2008 – Aug 2014

Customer Service Manager

- Management of colleagues and providing on-site training as well as assisting in any over-the-counter issues.
- Ensuring a safe working environment for my team.
- Arranging and participating in several marketing events (e.g. World Cup, Grand National, Fixed Odds Betting Terminal tournaments) and making sure my team are engaged in the events.
- Monitoring business levels and providing solutions to increase footfall, turnover and profit margins.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

GREATER MANCHESTER POLICE – OLDHAM DIVISION

Mar 2011 – Sep 2012

Special Constable

- Same responsibilities and powers as with regular Police Officer duties.
- Patrolling the local area to create visible presence as well as deter or handle criminal activity.
- Attending local events to ensure public safety and offer support.
- Involvement in organised operations to act against drug-related criminal activity.
- Working with Response Officers to respond to '999' emergencies.

HOBBIES, INTERESTS & REFERENCES

HOBBIES & INTERESTS











Gaming

ina

Travelling

Languages

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.